## **Azmine Toushik Wasi**

+880 1521 526792 | <u>azminetoushik.wasi@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Facebook</u> | <u>Kaggle</u> | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Website</u>

### **Summery**

An idealist with distinguished experience, and expertise in Programming, IT Automation, Design, Ed-Tech, Product & Content Development and Project Management. Currently, exploring Data Science, Machine Learning and IT Automation. Love to learn new things, improve existing skills, experiment with acquired skills and challenge my capabilities.

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming Skills: Python, R, C

Data Related Skills: Excel, PowerBI, Tableau, SAS Visual Business Analytics, SQL,

NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Machine Learning Skills: Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras, Pycaret

### **Education**

Feb 2020 - Present

Bachelor of Science (Engr.) in Industrial and Production
Engineering
Shahjalal University Of Science And Technology

• Expected to complete in 2024

### **Work Experience**

Mar 2022 – Present Started working here at Jun 2021 Project Executive - 10 Minute School (Part time)

• Content quality, performance and distribution analytics

• Team Lead, Content Design, 10 Minute School- Jobs

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

**Live-Class Resource Executive - Shikho** (Part time)

• Preparation and quality 500+ Live-Class materials.

Content and performance analytics.

### Organizational/Voluntary Experience

Sep 2022 – Jan 2022 Started working here at Nov 2020 Wing Director, Technical Facilities Enhancement – *Black Brains* 

• Lead, Micro-course and App Product Development

Regular technical R&D and improvements.

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

Judge, The Queen's Commonwealth Essay Competition 2021 – *Royal Commonwealth Society* 

• Member of the judging panel of the competition with 26,000+ submission

Sep 2019 – Present

Online Volunteer - United Nations Volunteers

Data, Translation, Design and consulting based projects

Mar 2019 - Oct 2021

Information Technology Manager - Bangladesh Youngster
Social Organization

• Developed App, Website and other IT Structures for the organization and increased productivity by 350%.

#### Other Skills

Data Analytics, Visualization, Microsoft Word – Powerpoint - Access, Google Tools, Communication, Team Management, Teamwork, Proficient in Bangla and English

### **Virtual Internships**

Aug 2021	<ul> <li>Data Analytics Internship   EntryLevel</li> <li>Data Analytics , Business Modeling</li> <li>Used MS Excel, Power BI</li> </ul>
Jun 2021	<ul> <li>Engineering: Undergraduate &amp; Masters   Forage - Microsoft</li> <li>Software Engineering, Design, Engineering thinking</li> <li>Data Analytics, Business Modeling</li> </ul>
Mar 2021	<ul> <li>Data@ANZ Program   Forage - ANZ</li> <li>Data Science (Used Scikitlearn - Linear Regression)</li> <li>Exploratory Data Analysis - Predictive Analytics</li> </ul>
Apr 2021	<ul> <li>Open-Access Data Science &amp; Advanced Analytics Forage   BCG</li> <li>Data Science and Problem Structuring</li> <li>EDA, Feature Engineering, Mathematical Modeling</li> </ul>

#### **Prizes and Awards**

GDN Presenta - Champion | Podiam 1.0 - 2nd Runners Up National High School Programming Contest - 2016 and 2017 - Regional Winner; National Top 30 in both

Inter School & College Programming Contest '19 – **Regional (3<sup>rd</sup>) – National Top 30**Queens Commonwealth Essay Competition 2019 – **Silver Award**National Earth Science Olympiad 2019 – **National Winner**Bangladesh Physics Olympiad 2019 Comilla Region – **5th** 

### **Learning and Certifications**

### <u>Professional Certificates (Coursera):</u>

- DeepLearning.Al TensorFlow Developer
- SAS Visual Business Analytics

### <u>Google Career - Professional</u> <u>Certificates (Coursera):</u>

- Data Analyst
- IT Automation with Python
- IT Support Professional
- Project Management

#### **Edx Courses:**

- IBMx DS0105EN: Data Science Tools
- Harvardx PH526x: Using Python for Research

### **Coursera Specializations Completed:**

- Python 3 Programming
- Applied Data Science with Python
- Data Analysis and Visualization

### <u>DataCamp Learning Paths Completed:</u>

- Career Tracks: Python Programmer,
- Skill Tracks: Machine Learning Scientist with Python, Python Programming, Python Fundamentals
- Python Advanced Level Proficiency
   DataCamp Certified

### <u>LinkedIn Learning Paths Completed:</u>

- Software Developer
- Data Analyst
- · Financial Analyst

# <u>IBM Developer Skills Network</u> <u>Programs:</u>

- Data and AI CP4D Journey Intermediate
- Python for Data Science Program

### **Frecodecamp.org Certifications:**

Data Analysis with Python